martin**mads**en software developer, me@martinbjeldbak.com

about

7/56 Hood St Sherwood 4075 Queensland Australia

26 years old +61 413 043 210 martinbjeldbak.com nartinbjeldbak in / martinbjeldbak

languages

bilingual Danish/English IELTS score: 8.5

programming

Ruby on Rails Heroku, AWS (EC2, RDS, ECS, S3), SQL CircleCI, GitHub Actions LATEX, HTML, Git JavaScript (ES6, React) OS X, Unix

interests

machine learning, devOps TDD, functional programming service oriented architecture web development

experience

since 2016 **Lead Software Developer, Backend** NetEngine, Brisbane, Australia

Ruby on Rails software developer working with our clients to build web-based systems across many different industries, from finance to flood mapping. I work on setting up infrastructure in AWS using CloudFormation, to building service objects in Rails and avoiding circular dependencies. I also partake in non-technical activities such as business planning, training new backend developers, etc.

2012-2014 Student Software Developer Falck Healthcare a/s, Aalborg, Denmark

Development of Ruby on Rails-based system used daily by ca. 40 of Falck's

physiotherapists to journal their patients' treatments and wellbeing.

2010-2014 Ran my own small company developing and hosting web sites for clients.

education

2014-2016 M.Sc. in Computer Science Aalborg University (AAU), Denmark

Majoring in Computer Science (120 ECTS) Specializing in Machine Intelligence

2014-2015 Studying abroad University of California, San Diego (UCSD), USA

Fully accredited as part of the first year of my master's degree from Aalborg

University

2011-2014 **B.Sc.** in Computer Science Aalborg University (AAU), Denmark

Majoring in Computer Science (180 ECTS)

2008-2011 Student

EUC Nord - Technical Gymnasium of Hjørring, Denmark

Focus in physics and engineering

other activities

2013-2014

Student member of the Study Board

Aalborg University (AAU), Denmark

Elected position. Handling of educations within Computer Science curricula at the university, quality assurance of education, handling of exemptions, etc.

projects

2015 University of California, San Diego, O / martinbjeldbak/xquery-processor

Implemented a subset of the XQuery and XPath XML query languages in Java

2016 A Hierarchical Tree Distance Measure for Classification martinbjeldbak.com/thesis.pdf

Concluded my M.Sc. degree. Published in Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Pattern Recognition Applications and Methods - Volume

1: ICPRAM 2017, pages 502-509

...and many other projects! I contribute as much as I can to open source and work on other projects for fun. For more examples, feel free to check out my GitHub profile, linked above.